本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
赤葦
Akaashi...
今日はもう俺に上げんな
Don't set for me anymore today!
Okay.
わかりました
Huh?
But in exchange, please calm down.
じゃあ上げない間に落ち着いてくださいね
I don't know what's going on,
but their ace doesn't seem to be doing well!
よくわかんないけど向こうのエスが不調ぽい
Let's keep it up!
畳み掛けるぞ
Yeah!
しゃあ
Episode Eleven:
"Up Above"
All right!
Nice spike!
ナイスキです
Yeah!
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
All right!
よしゃ
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
き気のせいでしょうか
M-Maybe I'm just imagining it,
but it doesn't seem like Fukurodani is fazed at all.
全然崩れませんね梟谷
Yeah...
Here's a chance!
チャンスボ
Here.
今梟谷の前衛の攻撃は２枚
Right now, there are two attackers up front for Fukurodani.
Will they do a fast attack from the middle,
ここはセンタからの速攻か
a back row attack,
バクアタクか
それともさすがにそろそろ４番来るか
or will number four finally come back?
ツアタク
A setter dump!
Fukurodani's back in the lead!
Karasuno                   Fukurodani
梟谷逆転し返した
And the ace hasn't even scored once!
エスは一本も打てないのに
Bokuto may look like the eldest son of the family,
but he's actually the youngest.
木兎てさ一見「長男」て感じだけど
実際の所「末子」なんだよね
Nice, Akaashi!
ナイス赤葦
Thank you.
Though he is the strongest individually.
ありがとうございます
単体では最強だけど
Nice receive!
ナイスレシ
木兎の不調なんて慣れこなんだよ
We're used to Bokuto's slumps.
The smallest thing can make him happy or depressed.
ちょとしたことですぐ上がたり下がたりするからな
Left!
レフト
What are we gonna do with him?
しょうがねえなもう
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
All right!
よしゃ
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
梟谷マチポイント
Fukurodani's on match point!
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
Just one more point!
あと１点
梟谷は木兎が引張るチムつより
I guess Fukurodani isn't a team that Bokuto leads, but one where the team leads the way for him.
他のメンバ全員で木兎を引張るチムてことか
ワンチ
I touched it!
梟谷が木兎さんのワンマンチムじゃないことはわかた
I understand now that Fukurodani isn't a one-man team of Bokuto.
That said...
それでも
He's definitely the scariest person on their team.
単体で木兎さんより怖い人はいないでしょ
Totally shut out!
どシャト
All right! Just one more point for a deuce!
よしあと１点でデュス
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
Wow...
Well done.
上出来
If I mess up the serve here, the match will instantly end.
ここでサブをミスれば即試合終了ここは
I'll...
definitely make this one land!
確実に入れていく
Komi!
小見やん
しゃあ
Yeah!
Nice receive!
ナイスレシ
烏野はそろそろうちがどういうチムかわかた頃
I'm sure Karasuno's figured out
what kind of team we are by now.
つまりエスから意識が逸れる頃
Which means their attention is off of the ace.
そして木兎さんは打ちたくてそわそわし出す頃
And he wants to spike so bad that he's getting fidgety!
We'll let you have the spotlight.
おいしいところはくれてやる
So...
だから
pick yourself back up...
ささと復活しろエス
ace!
Karasuno                     Fukurodani
Please.
お願いします
Leave it to us.
任せろ
Nice job, Ace!
よエス
That was awesome!
カコイイね
In the end, it just has to be the ace!
やぱ最後はエスですなぁ
Oh no! It's a raptor!
キャ猛禽類
Your hair's like a great horned owl!
ミミズクヘド
やぱり俺最強
I'm truly the best!
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey...
相変わらず上がるのも早いね
He's able to pick himself back up so quickly.
So that's what you call simple-minded.
あれが単細胞てヤツか
The weakness of their ace draws out the strengths of the other members.
エスの脆さが他のメンバの強さを引き出し
And at the same time, it becomes
the root that holds the team together.
同時に簡単には崩れない根この強さになてる
I guess that's another form of strength.
こういう強さもあるわけか
正直木兎君さえ止められればあるいはと思ていたんですが
To be honest, I was thinking we might be okay if we
were able to stop Bokuto, but I guess that was naïve.
甘かたですね
I bet he's allowed the freedom to do
whatever he wants without them caring
あれだけ自由且つ我が儘でいられるのもそれを放置できるのも
Aren't I awesome, Akaashi?!
やぱオレ強ぇなあ赤葦
お互いの信頼関係があてこそだろうな
because they have complete faith in one another.
そうですね木兎さん
For sure, Bokuto.
うちはまだまだズケズケと我が儘言える程の仲じゃないからなぁ
Our team just isn't at the point where any of them can be that selfish yet.
I'm sorry!
すまん
That last serve was a total meatball because I chickened out!
最後のサブビビて
「どうぞ攻撃してください」てサブ打ちまた
If you can realize that all by yourself, you're doing just fine.
それが自分でわかたんなら上出来だ
What determines whether you can win or not
is how aggressive you can be in situations like that.
あの場面でどれだけ攻められるかが
勝ち上がて行けるかどうかを左右する
Nobody wants to end a match
because of a mistake they made.
誰だて自分のミスで試合終わらせたくねぇし
He's talking about you.
お前のことだな
Shut up!
うるせぇよ
But nobody will blame you for trying to hit a serve to take the win, either.
「勝ちに行くサブ」を打とうとするのを非難する奴なんかいねぇよ
Yes, sir!
Anyway, that was one hell of a losing streak we went on.
でもまぁ終わてみれば見事な負けぷりなわけだが
Though one thing is for certain.
一つだけはきりしてる
Your offense will work against the top teams in the country!
お前達の攻撃は全国相手に通じる
今君達はサブもコンビネションも他のチムには敵わない
Right now, your serves and combo attacks are no match for our opponent's.
This is no surprise since you guys started practicing them way later.
後から始めたのだから当然ですね
But that doesn't mean you should give up.
でも止めてはいけません
Don't think that you've reached your limit.
「自分の力はこのくらい」と思てはいけません
You know how when you mix colors, they become muddled and dirty?
色は混ぜると濁て汚くなていきますよね
でも混ざり合た最後はどの色にも負けない黒です
But once you finish mixing, you get the color which no other can overtake—black.
Please make our team black, a fitting color for crows.
烏らしく黒のチムになてください
W-Was my metaphor too difficult to understand?
例えが難しかたかな
No! Thank you very much, sir!
いえありがとうございました
Thank you very much, sir!
ありがとうございました
All right, time our last penalty of the training camp!
それじゃ合宿最後のペナルティ
フライング一周
One lap of diving drills!
Yessir!
Asahi!
旭さん
There's still a little time left,
so could you hit some of my sets?
まだ時間あるんで俺のトス打てもらえませんか
Sure thing.
おおいいよ
Noya! Let me hit few too!
ノヤさん俺にも出してくれ
Sounds good, Ryuu!
おおもちろんだぜ龍
Oh, me too.
俺も
上げてくれるんすかスガさん
You'll throw them up for us, Suga?
That'll be perfect!
アザス
Um, not exactly.
違う違う
打つ方
I'm gonna spike.
Damn it.
速攻がもと成功してれば
If we'd practiced our fast attack just a bit more,
we might've been able to take a set off of Fukurodani.
梟谷からセト取れたかもしんねぇのに
But we have a way to fight them now.
でもこれで戦える
読まれたり追いつかれたりしても
Even if they can read our moves or catch up to us...
we can fight!
戦える
俺のトス次第だろ
That all depends on my sets.
It's fine. You'll get there eventually.
お前はそのうちやるから大丈夫
Don't tell me what I'm gonna do!
人のこと勝手に決めんじゃねぇ
Are you saying you won't?
じゃあやれねぇのかよ
Of course I'll get there eventually, moron!
やれるに決まてんだろボケェ
やるんじゃねぇか
So I was right!
Let's go practice that fast attack!
ちょとでも速攻の練習やんぞ
会話から滲み出る頭の悪さ
It's a good thing being that stupid isn't contagious.
Yeah!
よしゃ
We head straight into the spring tourney prelims as soon as we get back.
戻たらすぐ春高一次予選だな
ああ次俺達がここに来るとしたらその後か
Yeah. The next time we'll come back to Tokyo will be after that.
I hope it won't be as hot then.
そん時はいくらか涼しいかな
Nah, it'll probably still be warm.
残暑がある残暑
What's his problem, Suga?
どうしたんだスガ
If we don't make it through the prelims,
the three of us won't be able to come back.
突破できなきゃ俺達はもう来れないわけか
Oh look, it's Mr. Gloomy Goatee!
出たネガティブヒゲ
Wh-What...
Of course we'll be coming back, moron!
また全員で来るに決まてんだろボケェ
You're right. Sorry.
そうだなすまん
Begone, gloom!
ネガティブ退散
Actually, you sounded like Kageyama just now.
つか今の影山の言い方に似てる
ボケェ日向ボケェ
Moron! Hinata, you moron!
似てる
It's perfect!
もかい
Do it again!
I-It feels like I'm getting an extra scolding somehow...
なんか余分に怒られてる感じする
What?
Hell yeah! It's meat time!
おし肉だ
I could eat an entire cow!
腹減た
お皿宮ノ下さんの方に持て行て
Take the plates over to where Miyanoshita is.
Sure.
よいしょ
There we go.
木兎さんにも不調な時があるんですね
So even Bokuto has slumps.
Yeah. He sometimes self-destructs in bizarre ways.
まぁよくわかんないところで自滅するからね
On the other hand, he doesn't care how good our opponents are, so it works out in the end.
でも敵が強いことに凹むてことはないから割と大丈夫
When everyone else on the team loses hope, he's usually still pretty energetic.
他のメンバ皆が心折れそうな時は大抵一人だけ元気だしね
Despite everything, he's pretty reliable.
なんだかんだで頼りになるよ
Bokuto!
木兎さん
Oh?
W-We're not gonna lose in an actual match!
ほ本番では負けません
Oh yeah?! Bring it on, then!
受けて立つぜ
Before spring nationals,
春高の前にまずは
お肉争奪戦だぜ日向
we need to have our meat war, Hinata!
Ahem.
１週間の合宿お疲れ諸君
Thank you for all the hard work
in this week-long training camp!
Tasty food smiles at the sound of hunger.
空腹にこそウマいものは微笑む
Feel free to repair your muscles as much as you wish!
存分に筋肉を修復しなさい
Thanks for the food!
いただきます
So then, Kenma...
でさ研磨の奴が
Stop right there!
木兎てめぇ横取りすんじゃねぇこのヤロウ
Don't steal my food, you bastard!
おにぎりどうぞ
Have some rice balls too!
Oh, thank—
いただきま
What?!
わかているな龍
Do you understand, Ryuu?
Of course.
当然だぜ虎
Tora?
Yes, Master.
はい師匠
Do not allow for any dudes to use these
good spirits as an excuse to approach Kiyoko!
このタイミングでうかれついでに潔子さんに近づく輩を決して許すな
仰せのままに
As you wish!
Go!
行け行け
You go!
お前行けよ
Why is Nishinoya the master?
なんで西谷さんが師匠なんだろ
Apparently, it's because he's the only one to have been slapped by Shimizu.
清水先輩に唯一平手打ちを食らたことのあるツワモノだかららしいよ
Ah...
月島
Tsukishima!
You need to eat more!
もと食べなさいよ
There's no way I can eat that much.
いや僕はそんなには
C'mon! Eat some veggies too!
ホラ野菜も食えよ
Kenma! You eat some too, damn it!
研磨もだコラ
米を食えよ
Eat some rice!
You mean meat! Eat some meat, Tsukki!
肉だろ肉を食えツキ
You won't grow big otherwise!
大きくなれないぞ
親戚のおさんか
Are they, like, some pushy uncles?
And he's the young, defiant nephew who can't stand them.
そしてウザがる現代子
気付いて面白がてるな主将連中は
The generals totally see that and are having fun with it.
Hey, Suga.
なあスガ君
One of your managers is acting really strange. Is she okay?
烏野のあの子挙動不審だけど大丈夫
Th-This is like...
ここれはまるで
a jungle of giants!
巨人の密林
The meat smells so good... I wanna eat some...
お肉の匂い食べたい
でもこんなところに突入したら間違て食われるやも
もうできあがたのか
Is this done already?
But if I carelessly rush in there, they might eat me by accident!
Hey, I was planning on eating that!
あそれ俺が食おうと思た
Or worse, barbecue me!
焼かれるやも
Can you reach? Would you like me to get you something?
届きますか何か取る
I promise I don't taste good!
私美味しくないです
Er, I mean, I'm fine! Thanks!
じゃなくてはい大丈夫です
I was thinking about eating this.
今これをいただこうと思てまして
おおいしい
I-It's delicious.
人生のような味がします
It tastes like real life...
Yacchan? The one you just ate looked really charred. Are you all right?
やちゃん今食たやつすげぇ黒かたけど大丈夫
お茶いる
Want some tea?
水もありますよ
There's water too.
Doesn't that look a bit sketchy to you?
なんかあそこの絵面がやばい
Yeah...
町中だたら通報されそうすね
They'd probably get the cops called on them if this was in the city.
I definitely wouldn't want to be surrounded by them.
囲まれたくねぇ
俺はあちに囲まれてぇ
I'd much rather have them surround me.
Karasuno's third-years seem like they have their act together.
烏野の３年生てしかりしてそうですよね
Our managers are all quite beautiful,
わが梟谷グルプのマネちゃんズはレベルが高いが
but with Karasuno joining us,
I think it has gone up one notch further.
烏野が加わてそれが更に上がたと思うが
What do you think?
どうだろう
I cannot argue.
異論ありません
Our ace is pretty weak-willed, though.
エスはメンタル弱いけどね
What? Really?
そうなの
He sure looks scary.
あんなに怖そうなのに
That's probably better than having such a simple-minded ace.
でも単細胞エスよりはいいと思うな
What?!
You're in the nation's top five?!
全国で５本の指すげぇぇ
That's awesome!
だろうだろう
Right? Right?!
Ushiwaka from your region is in the top three, you know.
でもお前らんとこのウシワカは３本の指に入てくるやつだぜ
Top three?!
３本
Hey! That really hurts, you know?!
おいそんなこと言たら俺は霞んじゃうじゃねぇか
Three? Who are the other two?
３本てことはあと２人いるてことすか
東北のウシワカ
Ushiwaka from the Tohoku region,
九州のキリュウ
Kiryuu from the Kyushu region,
関東のサクサ
and Sakusa from the Kanto region.
Those are the three best aces in the country this year.
これが今年の全国高校３大エス
そのうちの一人がよりによて宮城に
One of those three is in Miyagi of all places.
Hey, Tsukki!
おいツキ俺のスパイク相手に散々練習したのに
You practiced a ton against my spikes!
ウシワカにビビるなんて許さん
I won't allow you to be intimidated by Ushiwaka!
Could you please not call me that?
ツキてやめてもらていいですか
Besides, just because they're the best doesn't mean their teams are the top three teams in the country.
それにエスがトプ３だからて
チムもトプ３てわけじゃねぇぞ
Yeah! Exactly!
そうだそうだ
まあサクサのいる井闥山は優勝候補筆頭だけどな
Though Sakusa's team, Itachiyama,
is the odds-on favorite to win spring nationals.
Then...
じゃあ
それを倒せば日本一ですか
...if we beat them, we'll be number one?
言うねヘタクソトプ２
Strong words coming from the
top two at sucking in the country!
Hinata must be number one.
日向が１位か
Kenma said that my serves and receives were better!
研磨がサブもレシブも俺のほうがうまいて言てたぞ
D'oh!
Coach Nekomata.
猫又先生
Again, thank you very much for inviting us.
今回も呼んでいただいてありがとうございました
In the end, you couldn't stop my spikes, Tsukki!
結局俺のスパイク止められなかたなツキ
ここに来られたからこその変化もあたみたいです
It appears their change happened because we came here.
No thanks needed. We got some good motivation too,
so it was mutually beneficial.
いやいやこちもいい刺激をもらたようだしお互い様だ
リエフがその猫を受け取たのか
Lev, you got a cat out of a tree?
Kenma's arms were too short, so he couldn't reach.
研磨さん腕短くて届かなかたからな
半年後には今と同じチムは一つも存在しない
Six months from now, not one team here will be the same team as it is now.
The members will change, forming new teams.
メンバの変わた新しいチムになている
Man, I'm stuffed.
ああ食た食た
They haven't yet played a match without any regrets.
Oh, so the prelims are later in Tokyo.
後悔の残らない試合など知らない
Well, we have a lot of schools.
Not that I've seen, anyway.
少なくとも俺は
それでも後悔のない試合をしてほしいと思うし
Still, I'd like them to play a match where they have no regrets.
All we can do to achieve that is give our very best.
そうであるよう力を尽くすしかないのだろうな
Right.
I hate being weak.
自分が弱いのは嫌だけどさ
Huh?
自分より上がたくさんいるつのは
But the fact that there are a lot of people up above me...
超わくわくすんなぁ
makes me really excited!
じゃあまたな
Well, see ya next time.
Yeah, 'til next time.
おまた
The summer vacation training camps...
夏休み合宿遠征
are now over.
全日程終了
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
The Japanese National High School Boys' Volleyball Tournament
Miyagi Prefecture Qualifier Preliminary Round Bracket
If we win twice in tomorrow, we'll go to the qualifiers in October to decide our region's representative.
明日の予選で２回勝てば
１０月の代表決定戦へ進出できます
The Japanese National High School Boys' Volleyball Tournament
Miyagi Prefecture Qualifier Preliminary Round Bracket
On top of the eight schools that make it past the preliminaries,
この一次予選を突破した８校に更に強豪８校を加えて
１０月の代表決定戦となります
eight powerhouse schools will go to that tournament in October.
We can only play two matches in the prelims?
一次予選は２回しか試合できないですか
俺たちはインタハイ予選でベスト１６まで行てるから
Since we made it to the quarterfinals in the interhigh prelims, we got a first-round bye.
一回戦は免除になてるんだ
Wow! We're awesome!
俺たちすげぇ
All right, let's start with stretches!
よし柔軟から始めるぞ
F-Finally... o-official matches...
いいよいよ公式戦すか緊張緊張してきた
Yessir!
I-I-I'm getting nervous now.
One, two, three, four...
一二三四
Oh, right. This will be your first tournament.
仁花ちゃんには初めての大会だもんね
Five, six, seven, eight...
五六七八
Yep.
Two, two, three, four...
二ニ三四
For us...
私たちには最後だ
五六七八
Five, six, seven, eight...
it's the last.
One, two, three, four...
一ニ三四
五六七八
Five, six, seven, eight...
Sorry! Please don't start crying!
ごめんごめん涙目にならないで
Two, two, three, four...
I-I'm not gonna cry! A mosquito just flew into my eye!
なてないす蚊が入ただけす
Five, six, seven, eight...
A mosquito?!
蚊が
さあ来い
Here I go!
Make it good!
来いや
Bring it!
Don't hit it to the libero. Don't hit it to the libero.
リベロには打たない
Don't hit it to the libero!
Why is it that it always goes there when I think that?
て思うと行ちゃうのなんでだろ
That was a good serve, Yamaguchi!
山口ナイサちゃんと取りづらかたぞ
It was hard to get!
Oh, right...
あはい
綺麗に拾われたけど
He dug it out perfectly, though.
もう一本
One more time!
何熱心に見てんだ先生
What are you concentrating so hard on?
Oh, Ukai.
烏養くん
いやうちの１年生もすごいんですが
Well, I was thinking that while our first-years are amazing, there are tons of other amazing first-years too.
他にもすごい１年生がいるものだなと思て
Yeah.
ああそいつか確かにな
That guy, huh?
Kakugawa Academy
He sure is something.
I'm home.
ただいま
Whoa, Kei. You grew even taller.
蛍背伸びたな
You totally passed me by a long time ago.
俺とくに越されたな
兄ちゃん
Big Bro.
Hey. Long time no see.
久しぶり
It's really been a while since we've gotten to talk.
蛍と話すのすげぇ久しぶりだな
Has it?
そうだけ
Even when I come home,
you usually never leave your room other than to eat.
俺が帰てきても飯ん時以外部屋にこもりきりだし
Is that so?
そうだけ
You look a bit different.
お前なんか顔つき変わたな
You went to that training camp, right? Was it rough?
遠征行てたんだろきつかた
It was normal.
普通
You've got "rough" written all over your face!
きつかたて顔してんぞ
You still play volleyball, right?
今でもバレやてるんでしょ
Yeah, I'm on a team.
おチムに入てるよ
Do you enter tournaments?
大会とかあるの
Yeah, we do.
お出るよ
You want to know why I'm still playing
after what happened in high school, am I right?
高校であんなだたのになんでまだやるのて
I'm still playing...
それはな高校であんなだたからだよ
because of what happened in high school.
I still really regret it when I think about it.
今思い出してもクソ悔しいし
I can't take anything good from the experience at all.
いい経験したて消化もできない
お前にもみともないとこ見せたしな
What you saw was such a disgrace.
何もやてないんだ高校で俺は
I didn't do anything in high school.
I didn't get to experience the
enjoyable parts of volleyball at all.
バレの気持ちいいとこ全然やれてない
But I've already experienced them.
でももう知ちゃたんだ
スパイク決める気持ちよさも
I know how good it feels to land a spike,
の誇らしさも
and how proud the roar of the crowd makes me.
その瞬間があるかないかだ
That one moment existing is the difference.
I want to be somewhere I can give it my very best until I'm completely satisfied.
気が済むまで本気でやれる場所にいたい
Right...
I see.
そうか
Ukai
You guys have a tournament starting tomorrow, don't you?
お前ら明日から試合だろ
You should wrap it up soon!
いい加減にしとけよ
One more! Just one more!
もう一本もう一本だけ
We'll finish after this one!
ラスト一本で切り上げます
Please!
お願いします
You know, this is the first time I've seen the tall boy.
あれあの大きい子初めて見るね
一本だけだぞ
Just one more.
Thanks!
He said he didn't get enough practice today
and begged to use our courts until we started.
あざす
今日はどうしても練習し足りないから
よし日向絶対決めるぞ
All right, Hinata! We're going to nail this!
うちらが始めるまでコト貸してくださいてさ
Yeah!
しゃあ
Let's do this, Kageyama!
影山ガンと来い
分かてんだよ
I know!
It seems he's the setter from Shou's school.
翔ちゃんとこのセタだて
Is that so?
Here we go!
行くよ
I've been watching for a while, but they keep messing up.
あたしさきから来て見てたんだけど失敗ばかりで
Whoa! Aone, have you gotten even taller?!
青根またでかくなてねぇ
あらら鎌先さんまた来たんですか
What's this? Dropping by again, Kamasaki?
暇ですか就活大丈夫ですか
Nothing better to do?
Having trouble finding a job?
シャツまくりすぎじゃないすか
Aren't your sleeves rolled up too far?
二口てめぇ先輩をもとありがた
Futakuchi, you punk! You should be more appreciative of your—
Hey, Kunimi.
な国見
Was that story Oikawa told for real?
及川さんのあの話て本当かな
Seemed real to me.
本当なんじゃないけこうムチャするじゃんあの人
I mean, he does pretty reckless things.
What? Torino?
えトリノ
It's Karasuno.
カラスノだてば
どこそれ知らねぇ
Where's that? Never heard of it.
If we can defeat Shiratorizawa,
no one else in the prefecture stands a chance.
白鳥沢に勝てる強ささえあれば
県内のどこにだて勝てるだろ
単純じゃん
Simple as that.
Better too big than too small
コンクリト出身日向翔陽です
I'm Hinata Shouyou, from the concrete.
あなたをぶ倒して全国へ行きます
I'm gonna crush you
and go to nationals.
もう一本
One more.
August 11th.
８月１１日全日本バレボル高等学校選手権大会
The Japanese National High School
Volleyball Championship Tournament,
通称春の高校バレ
A.K.A. the Spring Volleyball National Tournament.
The preliminary round of the
Miyagi qualifiers begins today!
宮城県代表決定戦一次予選
当日
Sometimes just having a super tall guy can be the difference between victory and defeat!
超でかいやつがいるだけで勝敗分けることもあるんだぞ
I'm not tall enough that you need to add "super."
僕「超」がつくほどでかくないけど
Height is a weapon in its own right!
身長はそれだけで武器なんだて可愛くねぇな
You're so not cute.
１９０センチ近い男に可愛さ求めないでよ
Please don't look for cuteness in a guy who's almost 190 cm tall.
Episode Twelve:
Let the Matches Begin!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ試合開始
"Let the Matches Begin!"